Personal Information

Name: Long Liang

Phone Number: 02885223642

Email Address: lianglong|l1990@163.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/long-liang-0b8b03142/

Github: https://github.com/470024581/

Personal Statement

I have 10 years of software development experience before my master course. These working experiences cover front-end, back-end, server operation and maintenance, data analysis, big data, and machine learning. I have strong adaptability, quick response and enthusiasm for learning technology. I am proficient in multiple programming languages and have developed various projects during my master's studies. These projects cover full-stack applications and artificial intelligence agent systems, with a focus on integration and construction around the components of the LangChain ecosystem. Lifelong learning and continuous improvement.

Skill

Programming languages: Java、C#、Python、Scala、SQL、JavaScript、Shell.

Frontend components: JS React HTML.

Backend components: Spring、Redis、MangoDB、Node.js、Express.js.

Big data ecology: CDH、Hadoop、Spark、HBase、Doris、Kafka、Hue、Kylin、Superset.

Machine learning: SparkMLLib、Sk-learn、TensorFlow.

Al Agent: LangChain, LangGraph, MCP, Dify.ai.

Training and Certification

AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Academy Cloud Architecting - 2024

Alibaba Tianchi Precision Medical Competition (with 43th in the final round and 2522 individuals or teams participating) - 2016

Udacity Machine Learning Advanced Training - 2014

Education

2024-07~current Master's degree at the University of Auckland - Information Technology 2020-03~2022-07 Bachelor's degree at China University of Petroleum - Computer Science and Technology

Work Experience and Project

China Shanghai Jiuyu Software Systems Co., Ltd.

April 2023 ~ July 2024.

Role: Architect.

Project: Shanghai traffic card PB-level data center, construction of BI report system, responsible for the overall system design, development, team communication and coordination. The front and back end projects are built using React+Spring. Data warehouses are built around the Hadoop ecosystems for storage and computing. Data warehouse adopts a hierarchical design model.

China Shanghai FirstBrave Information Technology Co., Ltd.

September 2021 ~ September 2022.

Role: Architect.

Project: Build BI report system. Design and develop offline/real-time data warehouse, complete the calculation of indicators in each dimension, and provide business data monitoring and alarm. Optimize platform architecture to improve storage and IO efficiency.

China Shanghai Wm-motor Technology Group.

May 2018 ~ August 2021.

Role: Architect.

Project: Responsible for the construction of PB-level data warehouse and real-time computing system. Build your data center around the Hadoop and Spark ecosystems.

Cost reduction and efficiency increase: Migrate cold data to object storage to reduce storage costs. Optimize HDFS and HBase high availability architectures to improve data processing efficiency. Cloud server optimization, reduce costs by 50%, improve IO efficiency by 6 times, storage capacity by 22 times.

China Shanghai Liangxin Network Technology Co., Ltd.

February 2016 ~ April 2018.

Role: Senior Software Engineer.

Project: Responsible for the design and development of financial lending system user, activity module full stack development. The front and back ends are built using JQuery+JSP+Spring.

China Shanghai Hanzhiyou Information Technology Service Co., Ltd.

July 2012 ~ January 2016.

Role: Software Engineer.

Project: Responsible for the full stack development of user module, coupon module and supplier management module of e-commerce platform. The frontend and backend are built using Bootstrap+JSP+Spring.